Oketa Fred | Software Engineer

Location: Kampala, Uganda Telephone: +256 787 584 128 Email: oketafred@gmail.com

Professional Profile

To work and deliver adequate services at work and score maximum points of good quality, hard work and respect to my employer in my bid to attain professional success.

Core Skills

- HTML5
- CSS 3
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- Bootstrap
- Materialize CSS
- PHP
- Gulp

- Laravel/Lumen
- VueJS
- MySQL
- Git & Command Line
- WordPress
- API Integration & Development
- Agile Methodologies
- Jasmine

Career Summary

Oct/2019 - Present

Awamo Uganda Ltd, Kampala, Uganda Web Developer

Outline

Developing and Maintaining awamo's web applications ensuring that they meet globally accepted standards to achieve the best user experience.

Key Responsibilities

 Develop and maintain awamo's Cockpit, a large single page web application (management information system / BI solution).

- Align with the product management team about features, design/UI/UX and priorities.
- Align processes and data exchange with our transactional backend (open source, Java).
- Optimize design and code after the initial deployment.
- Participate in the full project life cycle from design to go-live and support.
- Improve automated testing procedures.
- Write documentation.
- Work with outside data sources and APIs.
- Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

March/2019 - Sep/2019

Refactory UG, Kampala, Uganda Software Engineer

Outline

Developing Front-End Documentation and Back End web based solutions for small business clients at leading Companies within Uganda. During my time at Refactory, I Worked with Xente as my partner company where we developed Xente Payment SDK that allows clients to Integrate Mobile Money Payment into their applications.

Key Responsibilities

- Integrating third party API's into systems and also work with outside data sources and APIs.
- Unit-test code for the new code addition to the code base.
- Develop upgrades for existing applications.
- Studied project management in software.
- Write documentation.

Feb/2019 - Sep/2019

Crystal Technologies Uganda Ltd, Kampala, Uganda Software Engineer

Outline

Developing Front-End and Back-End web based solutions for small business clients at leading Companies within Uganda. We integrated the eyenetra API, vaccination Microservice among others with CTI-Electronic Health Record System(EHR).

Key Responsibilities

- Developing Frontend of web based systems for clients.
- Integrating third party API's into systems.
- Developing Backend of web based systems for clients.
- Building and Deploying Websites for the Clients.

May/2018 - July 2018

Exclusive Lab, Tororo, Uganda Software Engineer

Outline

Developing Quality Websites and Web based systems for the different clients. I worked on the Busitema University Official website(2017 - 2018), Final Year Project Review System to track in-progress and already done final year projects for students of Busitema University.

Key Responsibilities

- Coding Front and Back end web based systems for different clients.
- Building and Deploying Websites for different clients using WordPress.

Education

August 2014 - May 2018

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Busitema University

Majoring in Software Development.

February 2012 – November 2013

Uganda Advanced Certificate of Education (UACE)

St. Joseph's College Layibi

Physics, Mathematics and Chemistry.

February 2008 - November 2011

Uganda Certificate of Education (UCE)

Gulu High School

Awards and Honors

Certificate of Achievement HTML 5

Awarded Certificate of Achievement by Cambridge Certification Authority after taking the HTML 5 Examination.

Certificate of Achievement CSS 3

Awarded Certificate of Achievement by Cambridge Certification Authority after taking the CSS 3 Examination.

• Learning Community Ambassador Facilitator

Awarded an opportunity to become a mentor and Learning Community Ambassador Facilitator with ALC in Tanzania between November 2018 to March 2019.

Google Africa Scholarship Front-End Course 2018

Awarded the Google Africa Challenge Scholarship 2018 to the Front-End Web Developer track in partnership with Google, Udacity and Andela Uganda.

• Google Developer Festival Eastern Uganda 2018

Selected to attend the 2018 Google Developers Festival Eastern Uganda in Mbale, Uganda.

Google Developer Festival Eastern Uganda 2017

Selected to attend the 2017 Google Developers Festival Eastern Uganda in Jinja, Uganda..

• Google Developer Festival Eastern Uganda 2016

Selected to attend the 2016 Google Developers Festival Eastern Uganda in Mbale, Uganda.

• Google Developer Festival Eastern Uganda 2015

Selected to attend the 2015 Google Developers Festival Eastern Uganda in Busia, Uganda.

• Google Developer Festival Eastern Uganda 2014

Selected to attend the 2014 Google Developers Festival Eastern Uganda in Busia, Uganda.

References

MR. AKOL SAMSON

ANDROID DEVELOPER / TEAM LEAD FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT +256 775 705 402 akol@awamo.com

MR. RONALD MUKASA KASENDWA

SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER +256 773 136 165

kasendwa@awamo.com

MR. OWOR YOAKIM

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER ANDELA UGANDA LIMITED +256 773 586 556 owor327@gmail.com